<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Portfolio website for Auguste Honore</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Portfolio website for Auguste Honore</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 31 Oct 2017 22:42:51 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Climate change</title>
      <link>/blogs/blog4/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Oct 2017 22:42:51 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blogs/blog4/</guid>
      <description>Climate change and temperature anomalies If we wanted to study climate change, we can find data on the Combined Land-Surface Air and Sea-Surface Water Temperature Anomalies in the Northern Hemisphere at NASA’s Goddard Institute for Space Studies. The tabular data of temperature anomalies can be found here
To define temperature anomalies you need to have a reference, or base, period which NASA clearly states that it is the period between 1951-1980.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IMDB ratings</title>
      <link>/blogs/blog3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Oct 2017 22:26:13 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blogs/blog3/</guid>
      <description>IMDB ratings: Differences between directors I explore whether the mean IMDB rating for Steven Spielberg and Tim Burton are the same or not. First, we load the data from the csv file and examine its structure:
movies &amp;lt;- read_csv(here::here(&amp;quot;data&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;movies.csv&amp;quot;)) #load data glimpse(movies) #examine the structure ## Rows: 2,961 ## Columns: 11 ## $ title &amp;lt;chr&amp;gt; &amp;quot;Avatar&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Titanic&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Jurassic World&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;The Aveng… ## $ genre &amp;lt;chr&amp;gt; &amp;quot;Action&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Drama&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Action&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Action&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Action&amp;quot;, … ## $ director &amp;lt;chr&amp;gt; &amp;quot;James Cameron&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;James Cameron&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Colin Trevorro… ## $ year &amp;lt;dbl&amp;gt; 2009, 1997, 2015, 2012, 2008, 1999, 1977, 2015, 2… ## $ duration &amp;lt;dbl&amp;gt; 178, 194, 124, 173, 152, 136, 125, 141, 164, 93, … ## $ gross &amp;lt;dbl&amp;gt; 7.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pay Discrimination</title>
      <link>/blogs/blog2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Oct 2017 22:26:09 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blogs/blog2/</guid>
      <description>Omega Group plc- Pay Discrimination At the last board meeting of Omega Group Plc., the headquarters of a large multinational company, the issue was raised that women were being discriminated in the company, in the sense that the salaries were not the same for male and female executives. A quick analysis of a sample of 50 employees (of which 24 men and 26 women) revealed that the average salary for men was about 8,700 higher than for women.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Airbnb Analysis</title>
      <link>/blogs/blog1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Oct 2017 21:28:43 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blogs/blog1/</guid>
      <description>Executive Summary Our main goal The main goal of this report is to analyze data about Airbnb listing in Istanbul and fit a model to predict the total cost for two people staying 4 nights in an AirBnB there.
 Our approach In order to tackle this problem, we have divided the work into 4 main parts
Exploratory Data Analysis (EDA) We used this part as an opportunity to clean our data and understand it by visualization</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello R Markdown</title>
      <link>/post/2015-07-23-r-rmarkdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2015 21:13:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2015-07-23-r-rmarkdown/</guid>
      <description>R Markdown This is an R Markdown document. Markdown is a simple formatting syntax for authoring HTML, PDF, and MS Word documents. For more details on using R Markdown see http://rmarkdown.rstudio.com.
You can embed an R code chunk like this:
summary(cars) ## speed dist ## Min. : 4.0 Min. : 2.00 ## 1st Qu.:12.0 1st Qu.: 26.00 ## Median :15.0 Median : 36.00 ## Mean :15.4 Mean : 42.98 ## 3rd Qu.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
